Guide to the Sierra Club Pennsylvania Chapter Records 1970-1997 AIS.2000.16
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Research Files, 1984-1991; III.
  - T-Y
    - Utility (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Water Contamination, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Water Quality (Box 11, Folder 13-15)
    - Weapons (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Wetlands, 1988-1990 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Wildlife, 1988-990 (Box 11, Folder 18-19)
    - Yellow Breeches Creek, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 20)
- Audio/Visual, 1985-1997; IV.
  Series IV consists of videotapes and cassettes related to Sierra Club activities, both at the national and state level. Included are promotional materials for Sierra Club membership and a video about the environmental positions of the 1988 presidential candidates. The materials date from 1985 to 1997.
  - Videotapes, 1.
    - The Natural Choice for the Gypsy Moth (17:55), VHS (Box 12)
    - Long Canyon- "Because People Love It" (6:46), April 21, 1989; VHS
    - We Are the Sierra Club (14 minutes), 1984; VHS
    - "N" Machine- International Symposium of the Telsa Society; Colorado Springs, CO, July 1988; VHS
    - Toxic Earth- The Need to Unite, OSHA Environmental Network (18 min.), VHS
    - Rohm & Haas, VHS
    - Overview of the Sierra Club, Media Coverage, 1997; VHS
    - Sierra Club Membership- The Front Lien of Conversation
    - Clean Air Trust- "Can't Breathe"; Environmental Information Center, January 16, 1997
    - Campaign '88- The Candidates Speak Out; Sierra Club
    - Ryder Waste to Energy Systems; Waste Distillator
    - Power to Dream; PA Energy Office (30 min.), June 30, 1988
    - Debate on State Park Resorts, (2 hours), May 9, 1989
    - State of the Commonwealth Address- Governor's Office (10:30 ert), January 22, 1992
    - "Under the Capitol Dome" with Senator John Schumaker, Topic: Household Hazardous Waste (28:30 ert), March 20, 1991
    - Toxic Earth- The Need to Unite; OSHA Environmental Network (18:24 ert)
    - 1992-1993 Budget Address Excerpts- Governor's Office, (8:35 ert), February 5, 1992
    - Acid Rain- The Cost of Combustion; WVIA-TV Documentary
    - Concord Resources Group- Public Meeting (2 hrs), March 28, 1991
    - Pier Program on Low Radioactive Waste (9:20 ert)
    - "Your Right to Know in Pennsylvania," IUP Media Communications
    - Northampton County Conservation District- Innovative & Alternative Technologies in Sewage Treatment Systems, August 8, 1990
    - Unlabeled
    - Northampton County Conservation District: Innovative & Alternative Technologies in Sewage Treatment Systems, VHS (Box 13)
    - Sierra Club LLRW Workshop Videos (5 copies), 3/4" U-matic Tapes
    - Conversations with Governor Dick Thornburgh (28:30 ert), January 27, 1985; 3/4" U-matic
    - Sierra Club- "Clean Air PSA's" (20, 30 and 30 secs. each), 3/4" U-matic
    - Medical Implications of Nuclear Energy- Set D, 3/4" U-matic
  - Microfilm, 2.
    - Department of Environmental Resources- Bureau of Radiation Protection, 1 box (Box 13)
  - Audio Cassettes, 3.
    - Beer Bottle Polka, Words & Music by A.J. Koveleski (4 cuts), 1985 (Box 13)
    - Sierra Club LLRW Workshop Cassette #1: Side 1-Bertel, Bertel Q & A; Side 2- Bertel Q & A, Cong. Edgar, Edagr Q & A
    - Sierra Club LLRW Workshop Cassette #2: Side 1- Edgar Q & A, Schmidt, Panel 1; Side 2- Panel 1 (Part 2)
    - Sierra Club LLRW Workshop Cassette #3: Side 1- Panel 2 (part 1); Side 2- Panel 2 (part 2)